# **Curriculum Vitae**

# Monika Srivastav

Plot No-L2/103 Shaheed Nagar

Agra: - 282001, Uttar Pradesh (India)

Mobile Number: +917618306452, 9354449224 E-Mail id: monikasrivastav842@gmail.com

#### SYNOPSIS

Secure a responsible position in the HR & Admin department, sharing my experience in performance management and employee engagement framework, along with interpersonal skills and ability to work across multiple stake holders to further the growth of the company.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Working with "Sony India Pvt.Ltd." As a "HR Coordinator (Contractual Role)".

Time Period: Dec 2022 to May 2023.

# **❖** Job Responsibilities

- Recruitment
- ➤ Coordination with Technical panel and understanding their requirements, defining job positions.
- Resourcing, screening and short listing resumes through various job portals or else internal reference.
- ➤ Short listing the resumes based on desired skills and experience.
- Advertising vacancies, screening and short listing resumes.
- > Conducting telephone and Personal interviews in coordination with department heads.
- > Preparing offer letter, Appointment Letter, completing joining Formalities and documentation
- Training & Development
- > Scheduling and arranging training while coordinating with external trainers and training programs.
- ➤ Identification of training needs and nominating candidates for training.
- Encouraging participation of employees in various organizational events.
- > Issuing training certificates after completion of the training.
- HR Administration
- Maintaining employee's personal files and records.
- Resposible for Onbording and Offboading of Employees.
- > Tracking attendance, maintaining leave records, etc.
- ➤ Generation of Experience Letters, Relieving Letters.
- Vendor Managment
- Employee Engagement
- ➤ Celebrations Diwali, Ganpati Festival, and other company events
- Effectively managing welfare measures, management employee get together, picnics & parties.
- ➤ Developing employee engagement programs like Initiated and administered a welcome-mail policy to all new joiners, Initiated regular Birthday mailers & celebration policy.

Worked with "Haier Appliances India Pvt Ltd." As a "HR/Admin officer". World's No. 1 brand of Major Appliances, a fast-growing consumer durables company.

#### Time Period: Nov 2021 to Nov 2022.

- Greeting Visitors
- Maintaining safety and hygiene standards of the reception area
- > Overseeing office services like cleaners and maintenance service providers
- Managing office inventory such as stationary, equipment etc
- Managing meeting room availability
- ➤ Handling transcription, printing, photocopying and faxing.
- Assisting the HR team with recruitment, onboarding and termination process.
- Assisting HR operation team in employee personal file management.
- Following upon the candidate interview status.
- > Preparation of new joined input.
- Employee history file records and management process Etc.
- ➤ Sending Employee birthday communication to team & distribution of birthday gifts to employee
- ➤ Visiting Management assisting OD team in employee engagement activities such as R&R Awards
- ➤ Managing Incoming & Outgoing Calls & Mailers.
- Vendor Management
- Managing Company Cabs,

# Worked as a "Customer Relationship Associate" in "Kauwwa.com" One of the fastest growing online food ordering and delivery platform.

# Time Period: January 2021 to August 2021

- ➤ Respond promptly and professionally to incoming customer inquiries in person, by telephone, or by email
- ➤ Maintain an updated knowledge of the organization's products, services, and customer service policies
- > Explain simply and clearly in response to customer questions and check for customer understanding and acceptance
- ➤ Recommend new products or services or make suggestions for improvements by identifying relevant features and benefits
- Assist clients by demonstrating the use of website and programs and answering any questions they may have
- ➤ Establish and maintain good rapport with customers by using positive language and anticipating their needs
- Forwarding and escalating inquiries to relevant individuals and departments.
- ➤ Working with a sales team to create better methods to address customer complaints

# Worked as a "Guest Relation associate" in "Omaxe Pvt Ltd."

# Time Period: August 2017 to March 2020

- Ensuring and providing flawless, upscale, professional and high-class guest service experiences
- Responding quickly and efficiently to guest concerns
- Assisting guests throughout the check-in process
- > Relating information about amenities and other relevant information for incoming guests
- ➤ Contributing to the development of customer satisfaction program
- ➤ Give the required information about different areas of our campus to the guest
- Foresee the needs of clients and ensure clients are satisfied with our services
- Address grievances issues and inform Guest Relations Manager as and when required.
- Record all necessary data and information in the designated registers everyday.
  Analyzing customer feedback and providing strategic direction to improve overall rating

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Awarded by the best employee of the month in "Haier India Pvt Ltd."
- ➤ Increased customer satisfaction with 25% by improving customer service.
- ➤ Attend 100% success in all customer service categories including communication skills, interpersonal skills, problem solving and friendliness.

# ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- ➤ Persuing **MBA** with specialization in "**Human Resource Management**" from Chandigarh University, Punjab (India).
- ➤ Bachelor of Commerce (passed in 2019) From Krishna College of Science and Technology, Agra affiliated from Dr. Bhim Rao Ambedkar University, Agra.

# **EXPERTISE**

Employee Relations Onboarding Performance Management Team work & Collaboration Project Management Skills Event Organizing Organization skills Time Management Skills Hr strategy creation Managing Priorities Leadership Skills Administrative Expert

# CERTIFIED PERSONALITY DEVELOPMENT COURSE

- Aptech aviation & hospitality academy Agra
- Language Enhancement (Mechanics of Grammar)
- > Language Enhancement (Phonetics &ESL).
- ➤ Health & Nutrition, Presentation & Communication Skills.

# **STRENGTH**

High Integrity	Effective Listening	Confident
Great Communication	Collaborative	Team Spirit
Punctuality	Conflict Resolution	Flexibility

# TECHNICAL QUALIFICATION

- ➤ Proficient in MS Office, Power Point Presentation, Exchange of online interface data via internet services.
- ➤ Well versed in V look up, H look up, Pivot Table, Sum if, Count if MS word.

# PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth : 18<sup>th</sup> September 1998

Nationality : Indian

Language Known : English, Hindi

# **Declaration**

I hereby declare that all the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief. I know that if any discrepancy will be found to the above information, I will be responsible for that.

Date: - (Monika Srivastav)